Togashi!
You guys need something?
We just got word of your fight with Takashima.
Yeah.
He should know better than to play his little tough guy games with me.
But he's an idiot and went for it anyway.
So I sent him straight and put an end to that.
By the way, if you haven't realized it yet, this mess is all their fault.
Their fault?
Who?
Do you mean the promoted players?
Togashi, what the heck happened between you guys?
You'll find out soon enough, no doubt.
Okay, listen up. We have three new members, at least for the next week or so. Consider this a trial period. I'm counting on you to help them if they need it. If all goes well and they prove to be skilled, they'll be invited to join Esperion Jr. next year. Your guidance is a pre-
Let me introduce myself. The name is Keiji Togashi. I'm a forward, and I plan on going pro someday. If you guys are some half-ass lazy team, you can forget about recruiting me!
What? Seriously? Togashi was invited here as a trialist when he was in the sixth grade?
Yeah, sure was.
Anyway, who cares? It doesn't matter. What are you doing in my room, creeps?
Uh, it's my room too, numbnuts.
I got demoted from the A-team, okay? After just one month, I wasn't good at anything. It's humiliating. Now get out of here!
What's up with you, Tachibana? You said you wanted to talk, but it sounds like you're looking for drama.
You want the tea on Togashi and Kurata's crew? Kind of weird, because I don't think you ever really talked to me.
Yuma, listen. I've made up my mind. Whatever it takes, we need to crush Musashino. No more doubts. I'm in this for the team. One hundred percent.
You should see the look on your face right now. Way to brood.
I don't usually invest in other people's problems. But what the hell. There's a popular saying in soccer, you know? It's kind of a sad generalization.
Youth players are mentally weak.
Not bad at all for a baby trainee.
Well, yeah, of course I'm not.
This is their basic training?
What they do every single day?
And act like it's nothing. So this is what a J-League team's academy is like.
Yo, Togashi.
Um, yes, sir.
I'm seeing quite a bit of improvement. Does that mean you've been practicing since last time?
You bet I have. I kept replaying what you taught me back then in my head, and then I kept practicing it. Over and over again.
Way to go, kid.
Tatsuya Fukuda. The guy who gave me advice when I met him at the National Center last year.
But come on, man. I finally get a chance to join the junior youth team, and now everyone's saying next year you're gonna coach youth.
I'm sure we'll work together one day. If you're lucky.
I'm so jealous of you, getting to talk to Coach Fukuda one-on-one like that.
Yeah, so? What the hell do you want?
That's funny. You actually do talk like a real punk. Nice to meet you. I'm Kuroda.
Huh. Other than Squinty, you're the only one who said two words to me. None of the others even tried.
Are all the players in this academy shy and quiet, or what?
I think it's just the way you talk to them at first.
What about these guys? No one talks to them, so it's not just me.
Well, everyone here is very focused on going pro, so we don't spend a lot of time socializing with each other.
You were amazing out there today, though. I mean, you managed to keep up with our training session. You've got a strong build and good technique.
So listen, we have a practice match with a local elementary school team this afternoon.
Wait, back up! So you're saying there's a game? That's incredible! Yes!
Before we go, why don't we try some stealth out on the field?
What do you mean?
Your height. We should make better use of it. You could try knocking the ball down in front of the goal, and then I could run onto it.
If that leads to a goal, it would be a great way to showcase your skills.
Awesome. There's fastened in actual games. They are in training.
If I join this team, I'll get to play at this level every day. It'll definitely help me reach my goal to go pro.
I couldn't have asked for a better shot.
You could try knocking the ball down in front of the goal to showcase your skills.
I don't like being made to provide assists, but if it means I can show off a bit, I'm all for it.
Stay there, Trilus! Don't move!
All right, go ahead!
Number six, go get in the middle!
Right!
Something that keeps bugging me, though, is it feels like they play differently with each other than they do with us,
who they're supposed to be training.
You're using different passes, and giving different instructions!
Sending a long ball your way, number six!
Time to show what I can do. You better get on the end of it, dude!
All right!
It's a one-on-one. Time to go and bury it!
What are you doing out there, noob? You had it!
Yeah.
What are you doing?
That shot was so easy.
You totally could have taken it.
Are you really asking me that?
Why didn't you do what you said you would?
The plan.
Huh?
Takashima, you were so cool out there!
Oh, hey, that's enough!
Well!
You invited your girlfriends to a practice match?
Um, who's this?
Uh, oh, he's a trialist.
No, neither of them are my girlfriend.
I just told them they could come along today if they felt like watching, and they did.
Takashima's really good at soccer, so it's always fun to see him play.
What's that face for? It's no big deal.
Really, we're having fun. I'm staying focused.
I keep soccer and my private life separate.
It could be worse, you know.
I could miss a chance to shoot while I'm in acres of space.
Asperion Jr. These guys are the top grade school players in Tokyo.
Everyone on the team has crazy skills, and their strength in matches feels impossible.
They all stay focused. None of them ever let their guard down.
So then why? Why am I so irritated by them?
You're leaving?
Yeah, they're on another level than us.
What? So? That's not a surprise. You knew they would be good.
If it was skill, we could work on it.
It's not.
It's them.
They're all so scary.
It's just not a good vibe overall.
Whenever they're around, it's like they don't even see us in front of them.
Makes me feel worthless, you know?
Yeah, well, so what?
Who cares if they look down on us?
They don't even look down on us.
They just...
They don't look at us. Period.
Didn't you feel like something was off during the game today?
I really don't know how else to explain it, but it was.
It felt like we were just there to use as tools for their training purposes.
I see now.
The reason something fell off is because none of them saw me as their equal.
I was just part of their stupid obstacle course.
You could try knocking the ball down in front of the goal.
And man, the scariest part is that I don't think they're doing it to be mean.
It's really freaky.
They're doing it unconsciously.
Huh?
Take care, Tokushi. Best of luck.
None of you got anything to say?
What do you think we should say?
Besides, you're staying, aren't you?
We'll just continue on without them.
By the way,
the reason I didn't shoot
was because I assessed the situation
and saw that you had a better chance of scoring.
Any more questions?
Do you just not like scoring?
That's the whole point of soccer!
That's the part everyone wants to do!
Well, if my overall goal tally helps me to become a pro, then sure.
But today was simply just another practice game.
So it didn't even count.
Got some advice for you, trialist.
You should wait until after you score to talk like that.
That play today was a mess!
All you have to do is kick it!
You fail as a forward if you can't even do that!
Who gets right up to the goal and then kicks it back?
The whole point is to score
and you had it all the way up there!
I suppose the answer is we're not like you.
I don't like this!
What's so different about us, huh?
Number 15, pass!
I can't think about that now.
If I want to join the team,
I've got to make those points happen!
Return!
Are they using me as their trial horse?
Fine.
Whatever.
This game is survival of the fittest.
Send it back!
I don't care what they do.
I'll continue to climb higher.
Togashi, the wing!
Play the ball out in front!
Yeah!
Nice leaker play, guys!
Very good!
Something's different today.
It doesn't feel like they're using me as practice for some reason.
All right.
This way I don't gotta hold back.
Hey, defense!
Let's go!
Come up through the middle!
What is wrong with that guy?
In the last game, he had zero problems going upfield.
Even though he's a center back.
What the hell is he looking at?
That's so weird.
They're not looking at the other team at all today.
So what are they looking at?
Yeah!
Chump!
Hey, Chump.
What's up?
So you can't shoot for yourself.
Jeez.
What now?
You still have a problem with me?
I want to know why all of you have been glancing over at that guy.
He wasn't here last game.
Isn't he the manager of the junior youth team?
Some bigwig is here, so now you're gonna change the way you play?
Is that what's different today?
Huh, Chump?
What's going on, you guys?
Your guess is as good as mine.
Hey, Red.
What's your deal?
Why didn't you push the defensive lineup?
What's the point of staying in your own half when we're attacking?
We've got to get goals to stay in the lead.
That's how it works, moron!
Hey, this is as far as we can push up.
We still have to watch out for counterattacks.
If a long ball were to go through to their forward, we'd lose the game.
And I can't be having that, you know?
Soccer's not all about scoring, Togashi.
Don't give me that crap, Chump.
I saw you racing upfield in the last match.
You don't fool me, Red.
You decided not to move up this time because the manager of the junior youth team's here.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Okay, you're dead wrong.
Anyway, I'm focusing on playing defense.
That's how I go pro.
Unfortunately for you, we're already past that scoring-is-so-fun mindset.
Grow up!
The reason I shot today was because I saw that I had a better chance of scoring.
Nothing more to it.
So that's all you care about?
You're playing soccer for the chance to go pro, that's it?
What other reason is there?
You don't like the thrill of winning?
Hey, what are those boys fighting about over there?
I have no idea.
We're all giving everything we've got.
None of us are slacking off.
So what the heck?
What's his dumb problem?
Hey guys, don't be so quick to rush upfield!
Of course we're playing to win.
What does he think?
I'll tighten up the defensive line and make sure of it.
We have to win.
Especially today.
What the crap?
Yes!
Three players are going for it, including the goalie.
That's not good.
I might be able to clear it, but I'll also crash into the goalpost!
Or a teammate!
Whoa!
Nice cover, Tokushi!
Hey!
Are you okay over there?
Don't get injured.
Become a pro.
Win!
Here at this academy, those are your priorities.
In that order.
And because that's the way you see things, you're always calculating too much and holding back.
What the heck are you talking about, weirdo?
Do you want to know what the worst part is?
You guys don't even know that you're doing it.
You've got no clue what your weaknesses are.
So when a do-or-die match comes along, you'll be useless.
You'll have no idea what to look out for.
So what's considered a do-or-die match to you?
Listen.
We're prioritizing becoming professional soccer players.
What's wrong with that?
Speaking for myself, if I can't go pro, then my purpose in life will be completely destroyed.
I'm always very aware of how I spend my time, the matches, and training.
I'm gambling my life on this goal.
It's everything I have.
Get it yet?
Our stakes are much higher than yours.
All of you are betting your lives on this way of playing?
Talk about stupid.
What did you say?
I can see both sides of it, actually.
It gives me a lot to think about.
I mean, I do feel bad for Togashi,
but I think Kurita made some very valid points, too.
Yeah, same here.
The whole idea is to go pro.
You gotta look at the big picture and make moves that are gonna get you to your end goal.
I was thinking of Musashino.
Their strength today was like Togashi's.
It's not about being right or wrong.
It's about being strong, no matter what.
I choose Togashi.
Please stop that!
Enough already, dude.
Get off!
If you hate the way we play soccer so much, why'd you join our team?
I came because I wanted to learn from manager Fukuda.
Got it.
Nothing to do with you.
Hey, you know, you're the only one who hasn't changed since sixth grade.
You're stuck in time at 11 years old, and you don't even realize it.
You've never stopped playing those academy soccer games.
Training's finally over.
I know we're prepping to play Musashino, but the same drills over and over is super rough.
I understand what Coach Nozomi's going for, but this tactic won't work if you don't already
have good ball skills.
So, do you think you and all the tryout guys are going to be able to pay-
What are you implying?
Especially him.
So, uh, they don't seem to be in a great mood.
It's understandable.
They're about to play against Musashino.
Damn it!
Everyone on the team is in a crap-fest mood!
I have to do something to bring them out of it so that we can work together!
But how am I going to do that when I've got to memorize Nozomi's super-tight team tactic?
Oh, this sucks so bad!
I don't even know what I could do to make this team work together.
Not like I can force them.
But I can't give up.
I have to say something that'll motivate them.
Hey!
Do you guys want to go on a picnic?
Do you want a stay-legged train?
Coach Nozomi's got a plan.
But it can only be mastered through repetition.
Regular training's not enough.
We all have to practice it.
Kuroda!
You're overworking yourself.
Is this because you're a starter?
Very interesting.
I know that Musashino is your old team and all.
But I haven't seen you do anything of note in the other league games.
Yeah, you're right.
To be honest, I'm scared.
I haven't slept much.
Not since the lineup was announced.
I'm afraid I'll play pathetically bad in front of all my old teammates and just screw it all up.
Hey, uh, you know you're saying this out loud, right?
Yeah, so?
It's just how I am.
That's just me.
I might be weak.
But I'm choosing not to run away this time.
Because I want to beat them.
Live up to Coach Nozomi's expectations.
But I can't do it alone.
So please, help me!
You're wrong.
You are not weak.
The ones who are weak are the ones who can't talk about weakness out loud.
Takashima?
You guys don't even know that you're doing it.
I'll tell you the truth.
Tachibana.
Aoi.
You may have heard this by now.
On the junior team.
Something that Togashi said to us.
Yeah?
The style we've developed since junior youth is the best there is.
I refuse to let Togashi slander it.
But what he said that day stayed with me all these years.
And there's a reason for that.
Truth is, after we fought, I finally realized that I had ended up saying some pretty shitty
things to him.
It has nothing to do with being in the academy.
It's something I'm struggling with personally.
If I am being weak, and I couldn't realize my weaknesses, that's on me.
I really want to get better.
Point is, Tachibana, I've decided to go with your strength.
I'll stay and train some more.
And you can count me in, too.
I'm still on the bench, but I'm available to help.
Really?
Let go of me.
Thanks, you guys.
All right.
Let's go!
Be strong.
In order to do that, I have to face my weaknesses.
So, you're gonna pretend you've decided you want to be a pro defender now?
How can you stand on that field without a clue as to what you're doing there?
Do I want to be a forward or a defender?
I'll decide for myself in the next match.
Against Musashino!
Next time on our washing, Tokyo Metropolis League Match 8, Tokyo Musashino Football Club Youths!